<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: email, | Roger Almeida's Opinion]]></title>
  <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/categories/email/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-17T22:38:22+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Roger Almeida]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My email Policy]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/06/15/my-e-mail-policy/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-15T10:11:44+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/06/15/my-e-mail-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was working for <a href="http://www.atos.net">Atos</a>, the company&rsquo;s CEO started a <a href="http://atos.net/en-us/home/we-are/zero-email.html">zero email initiative</a>. His aim was for the employees not to use email for internal communications. I remembered what I thought about it: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s impossible&rdquo;.
Now I believe he was right.
This post explains how I deal with my professional email inbox.</p>

<h2>Keep email closed</h2>

<p>I don&rsquo;t keep my email inbox open during working hours. I open it just when I have to. I also disabled my cellphone&rsquo;s email notification. That prevents me from checking email whenever I see a new one arrives.</p>

<h2>Schedule time to check email</h2>

<p>I check my email twice a day, at 10:00 am and 04:00 pm. I have reminders in my calendar. That helps me organize my day and prevents me from being fooled by my weak memory.</p>

<h2>Time box email time</h2>

<p>As an adopter of the <a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com/">Pomodoro Technique</a> I keep track of the time I spend checking email. What I noticed is that I need almost two pomodoros  to read/respond/forward/archive my emails. That means I need almost two hours of my day to deal with emails.  That was so true when I was working for <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">ThoughtWorks</a>. Now that I&rsquo;m working for <a href="http://dius.com.au/">DiUS</a> I&rsquo;m trying not to sign in to so many mailing lists. My aim is to keep my email time in one pomodoro.</p>

<h2>So far, so good</h2>

<p>Up until now I&rsquo;ve described what I have been doing for the past year. It has been working and I&rsquo;ve noticed my productive increased since then. Before I was checking emails every time I changed windows. Now, I don&rsquo;t suffer from that temptation. But there is one last step I wanna try&hellip;</p>

<h2>Vacation Responder On</h2>

<p>From now on I&rsquo;m keeping my <a href="https://support.google.com/mail/answer/25922?hl=en">Vacation Responder</a> on. This is my Vacation Responder reply:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hi,</p>

<p>This is an auto-reply to inform you about my email policy:</p>

<ul>
<li>I keep my email inbox closed during the working hours;</li>
<li>I also disabled email notifications in my cellphone;</li>
<li>I check email only at 10:00 am and 04:00 pm.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you need to contact me, feel free to reach me out by phone (XXXX XXX XXX), Whatsapp or Viber.</p></blockquote>

<p>I wanted to try it out for a long time, but never had the courage to actually do it. I&rsquo;ll give it a try. Who knows, maybe it becomes a new post.</p>

<h2>Credits</h2>

<p>This is not my idea, I read about it at <a href="http://vidaorganizada.com/comece/dicas/2-dicas-incriveis-de-produtividade-que-mudaram-minha-vida/">Vida Organizada</a> (pt_br only).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
