<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Roger Almeida]]></title>
  <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-11T13:02:38+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Roger Almeida]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Report to Boss" Stand-Up Anti-Pattern]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2016/11/25/report-to-boss/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-25T19:28:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2016/11/25/report-to-boss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>When the stand-up meeting is just a moment to report the work to the boss.</strong></p>

<p>Teams that are moving from a non-agile way of work to an agile way are under risk of bringing bad habits to the new world. One common flaw is the &lsquo;Report to Boss&rsquo; standup.</p>

<!--more-->


<h1>Report to boss</h1>

<p>In the Report To Boss Anti-Pattern, the team&rsquo;s members are not focused on the project progress. The team members are mainly concerned with giving a good report to the boss.
In this mode, team members speak looking directly to the boss. Sometimes they don’t even care if the others team members are able to listen to what they are saying. The whole stand up meeting becomes a public individual report to the boss.
It’s also common that the team members ask the boss to give them the next task. Sometimes the lack of autonomy is so high that the team members cannot determine the priority of their own task.</p>

<h1>Disadvantages</h1>

<p>The Report To Boss anti-pattern is just a symptom of some critical problems underneath.</p>

<h2>Lack of self-organization</h2>

<p>Self-organization arises from a team that has autonomy to determine its next tasks. A team should not wait for the boss to determine their next task. I&rsquo;m not saying that the boss (or PO, or customer, or manager, or &lsquo;you name it&rsquo;) should not determine priority. But once determined, the team should determine how to best perform the work. Without self-organization, all the improvements are expected to come from a single mind: the boss! If the boss cannot solve the problem(s), it is not uncommon that he will be able to blame someone else. In this situation, nobody is caring about the goals anymore.</p>

<h2>Comfort</h2>

<p>The agile methods are provocative. They move people out of their comfort zone. It’s outside the comfort zone where we have the best ability to innovate.
Sometimes the team members are comfortable with the boss taking all the responsibility. Some team members want to keep they responsibilities as small as possible . Letting the boss alone take all the important decisions by himself.
One of eXtreme Programming value is courage. XP defines courage as:</p>

<blockquote><p>We will tell the truth about progress and estimates. We don&rsquo;t document excuses for failure because we plan to succeed. We don&rsquo;t fear anything because no one ever works alone. We will adapt to changes whenever they happen.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>The inverse of courage is &lsquo;comfort&rsquo;.</p>

<h2>Unhealthy Environment</h2>

<p>This is the worst prejudice in my humble opinion. There are two scenarios:
The boss wants to concentrate all the power.
The team members don’t want to share responsibility.
These scenarios are not mutually exclusive. Both scenarios lead to unhealthy environments where people will work to  not be guilty.</p>

<h1>Solutions</h1>

<p>The first step is to identify if this anti-pattern is happening in your team and make it visible. When you identify the root causes  you can then try to find a plan to mitigate the root cause.
Some actions that I have seen to mitigate this problem are:</p>

<h2>Rotate the the person who facilitates the Stand-Up</h2>

<p>Try to move people out of their comfort zone. Make sure that you are doing it in a safe way, the goal is to make people see more than their solo task. But if you have some introverts in the team who don’t want to facilitate any session respect that.</p>

<h2>Ask the boss to change his behaviour</h2>

<p>If possible talk to the boss about this problem and its prejudices. Sometimes the boss is not even noticing that the problem is happening.</p>

<h2>Retrospective</h2>

<p>If possible, bring this problem to the next retrospective and discuss it with the team. Some people are so used to micro-management that they just can&rsquo;t see that this is happening. If the retrospective session is not enough to discuss the pros and cons try to set up a brown bag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I found a job in Sydney]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2016/04/08/how-i-found-a-job-at-sydney/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-08T14:53:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2016/04/08/how-i-found-a-job-at-sydney</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Seven components of my seek for work in Aussieland.</h3>

<p>In the last months I have answered the same recurring question:</p>

<p><strong>How did you find a job in Sydney?</strong></p>

<p>This post is a attempt to have a guide to point to describing some components of my journey to Sydney.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>English</h2>

<p><img src="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/images/learn_english.jpg" title="Learn English" alt="" /></p>

<p>To live abroad you have to at least speak English. So, if you can read this post it is a huge step. I studied English for 18 months and worked with it so I could develop it. Maybe I will create another post sharing how I learned English.</p>

<p><strong>Component 1: Learn English</strong></p>

<h2>Push yourself to the excellence</h2>

<p><img src="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/images/excellence.jpg" style="width: 60%; height: 375px; float: left; margin-right: 15px;"alt="Excellence"/> One thing that I didn&rsquo;t realize before starting this process was: I&rsquo;ll compete with the bests of the world. If you are a good professional and can easilly find a job at your current town. Good for you. That doesn&rsquo;t mean all the companies around the world will want you. Even if you are at Google. The concept of good/excellent professional changes from company to company. So keep pushing yourself to excellence. Be prepare to compete with the bests.</p>

<p><strong>Component 2: Push yourself to the excellence</strong></p>

<h2>Where to go?</h2>

<p><img src="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/images/destination-sign.jpg" style="width: 60%; height: 375px; float: right; margin-right: 15px;"alt="Excellence"/></p>

<p>I made a list of countries that I would like to live in: Canada, Australia, USA, Germany and Ireland. After some reflection, talks to my wife, and research time I put them in priority order:</p>

<ol>
<li>Australia</li>
<li>Canada</li>
<li>Germany</li>
<li>Ireland</li>
<li>USA</li>
</ol>


<p>I believe this is a MUST to everybody who wants to live abroad. You should know what you are looking for. If you don&rsquo;t have this PRIORITIZED list yet, do it now.</p>

<p><strong>Component 3: Create a prioritized list of destinations.</strong></p>

<h2>Update your <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a></h2>

<p>I used <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a> to find a job here at Sydney. <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a> works, believe me. But there&rsquo;s no free lunch. You have to spend time on your profile. In the late years I started give and ask for recommendations in my network. I also spend time describing my work in each position that I had. I have seen some people who want to find a job abroad but their <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a>  has no description of the work they did. Would you contract someone who cannot tell you what he did in the past. I don&rsquo;t produce a cv in Microsoft Word for years. I just keep my <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a> up-to-date and export it to PDF if needed.</p>

<p><strong>Component 4: Give love to your <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>

<h2>Search for positions</h2>

<p>Every night, after my kids and wife went to bed I spend between 1 and 2 hours searching for available positions. I followed the prioritized countries&rsquo;s list and used keywords like: Java, Ruby, Developer, etc&hellip;</p>

<p>My method was:</p>

<ul>
<li>I should cover page 1 and 2 of search result</li>
<li>I would only apply for companies that accepted either my <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a> profile or a PDF. I could not waste time filling forms.</li>
<li>I wrote a presentation letter to every single position that I liked. This took some time but it was essential.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;m pretty sure that I applied more than once for the same position. But I don&rsquo;t believe this is a big issue.</p>

<p>In two weeks doing it I had more interviews than I could handle. So after 2 weeks I stopped the search part and decided to see how the interviews would go.</p>

<p>The most important thing here is: Don&rsquo;t just seat in front of <a href="http://www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a> and randomly search for things. Develop a method, something that you can improve. For instance, during my first night of search I was filling forms. In the second night I skipped this companies and it improved my capacity of search. Follow a process and improve it.</p>

<p><strong>Component 5: Create a method to search for available positions. Follow it and improve it.</strong></p>

<h2>Interviews</h2>

<p>I had to accommodate the interviews in my day. As I was able to work from home, I could organize to be at home for most of the interviews. But I remember that one day I had to do a interview during lunch time when I was at client site. The good part was that most of the interview were outside working hours.</p>

<p>I failed in most of the interviews. I failed for Amazon in Ireland. No company in Canada wanted to offer me sponsor (I believe they expected me to get the visa by myself). For USA the problem is the Visa, you have to apply in a specific time-frame. Pivotal, for instance, liked my resume but we would have to wait till February to apply for a visa. But Germany and Australia were promising.</p>

<p>I went to the final round with eBay in Berlim and <a href="http://www.dius.com.au">DiUS</a> in Sydney.</p>

<p>People at eBay liked me, but they decided to pick another person with more mobile experience.</p>

<p>The process with <a href="http://www.dius.com.au">DiUS</a> was working fine, slow, but fine. I was on vacation during the last interviews. I did the big mistake of going to a isolated island in Sao Paulo/Brazil. The internet was not that good and the only lan-house closed at 09:00 pm. But in the end it worked out. On 23/12/2014 I received the job offer.</p>

<p><strong>Component 6: Organize your time and resource (e.g. internet)  for the interviews.</strong></p>

<h2>Iteration</h2>

<p><strong>This is the most important component: Repeat steps 1 through 6.</strong></p>

<p>One point that I would like to highlight is: I was prepared to start the search for positions again. It was not a single time thing. I decided to live abroad and I was willing to iterate the search step until I find a position suitable to me. So if you fail as I fail in most of the interviews, be prepared to try again. Reflect about what is working well and what you would like to improve and do it. Don&rsquo;t give up easily.</p>

<p>I hope this can help someone someday.</p>

<p>After receiving the offer another journey begins. The Visa! But this is a topic to future posts. Peace!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My email Policy]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/06/15/my-e-mail-policy/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-15T00:11:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/06/15/my-e-mail-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was working for <a href="http://www.atos.net">Atos</a>, the company&rsquo;s CEO started a <a href="http://atos.net/en-us/home/we-are/zero-email.html">zero email initiative</a>. His aim was for the employees not to use email for internal communications. I remembered what I thought about it: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s impossible&rdquo;.
Now I believe that he was right.
This post explains how I deal with my professional email inbox.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Keep email closed</h2>

<p>I don&rsquo;t keep my email inbox open during the working hours. I open it just when I have to. I also disabled the email notification in my cellphone. That prevents me from check email whatever I see that a new email arrived.</p>

<h2>Schedule time to check email</h2>

<p>I check my email twice a day, at 10:00 am and 04:00 pm. I have reminders in my calendar . That helps me organize my day and prevents me from being fooled by my weak memory.</p>

<h2>Time box email time</h2>

<p>As an adopter of the <a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com/">Pomodoro Technique</a> I keep track of the time I spend with email. What I noticed is that I need almost two pomodoros  to read/respond/forward/archive my emails. That means that I need almost two hours during my day only to deal with my email inbox.  That was so true when I was working for <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">ThoughtWorks</a>. Now that I&rsquo;m working for <a href="http://dius.com.au/">DiUS</a> I&rsquo;m trying not to sign in to so many email lists. My aim is to keep my email time in one pomodoro.</p>

<h2>So far, so good</h2>

<p>Up until here I&rsquo;ve described what I have been doing for one year. It&rsquo;s working fine and I&rsquo;ve noticed that my productive increased since then. Before I was checking email every time I alternated windows. Now, I can alternate windows without the temptation of checking email. But there is one last step that  I wanna try&hellip;</p>

<h2>Vacation Responder On</h2>

<p>From today on I&rsquo;ll keep my Vacation Responder On in my professional email. This is the message that I will send to those who send me email:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hi,</p>

<p>This is a auto-reply to inform you about my email policy:</p>

<ul>
<li>I keep my email inbox closed during the working hours;</li>
<li>I also disabled email notifications in my cellphone;</li>
<li>I check email only at 10:00 am and 04:00 pm.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you need to contact me before my email times, feel free to reach me by phone: XXXX XXX XXX. If you prefer you can use Whatsapp or Viber with this number as well.</p></blockquote>

<p>I wanted to try it for a long time, but never had courage to actually turn it on. I&rsquo;ll use it for some time, and depending on the feedback I will keep it or not. Who knows, maybe it can became a new post.</p>

<h2>Credits</h2>

<p>This is not my idea, I read about it at <a href="http://vidaorganizada.com/comece/dicas/2-dicas-incriveis-de-produtividade-que-mudaram-minha-vida/">Vida Organizada</a> (pt_br only).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to learn Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/02/01/how-to-learn-vim/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T14:40:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/02/01/how-to-learn-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a collection of adivces regards how to learn Vim. I collected this advices part during my learning process, part hearing|reading from my colleagues. I do believe that anyone can learning, or even master, vim though these advices.</p>

<!-- MORE -->


<h1>vimtutor</h1>

<p>At least once a week open a terminal and type: `vimtutor</p>

<h1>shortcutfoo</h1>

<h1>CheatSheet</h1>

<h1>vim adventures</h1>

<h1>vimcasts</h1>

<h1>pair programming</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Illusion of Competence]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/illusion-of-competence/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T16:15:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/illusion-of-competence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Cousera&rsquo;s</a> course <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/learning">Learning How to Learn: Powerful mental tools to help you master tough subjects</a>. It was a pleasant course with many useful informations and a lot of useful techniques to speed up my learning ability.
One point that caught my attention was the Illusion Of Competence and I would like to share with you how I added this knowledge to my day.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Illusions of Competence</h2>

<p>Our brain can fool us in many ways. When someone explains a subject and we could follow the explanation, we believe that we understood it. Furthermore we think that we are able to work with this new information. But we are not. Give you a example, think about learning to ride a bicycle. The only way to learn it is by doing it. That’s why when our teachers explained a subject to us, they as a rule gave us exercises to practice that subject.</p>

<h2>Illusions of Competence in a developer&rsquo;s day</h2>

<p>After doing the course I started paying attention to verify if I had some moments of Illusions of Competence in my day-by-day.  And indeed, it happens a lot. I could observe that during a <a href="http://www.quora.com/What-does-a-Thoughtworks-Inception-Workshop-look-like">Project&rsquo;s Inception</a> my colleagues and I heard explanations a few times. But when we had to use what we just learned we could not make a good use of it. This is because we didn&rsquo;t learned the subject. Or&hellip; Instead of acquiring competence in the subject we had a Illusion of Competence.</p>

<h2>How to avoid it</h2>

<p>After noticing that the Illusion of Competence was happening to me, actually us, I decide to fight against it. But, here comes the question: How?
The same way we did at school:</p>

<ul>
<li>Making questions</li>
<li>Explaining to a friend</li>
<li>Doing exercises</li>
</ul>


<h3>Making Question</h3>

<p>It was easy to do not value a explanation or be hard to focus on a explanation. One way to keep focus in a explanation is to get involved in the explanation, been part of it. Making a question is a good way to tell your brain that you are part of the explanation.</p>

<h3>Explaning to a friend</h3>

<p>When someone explain anything it&rsquo;s common to finish a topic saying:</p>

<ul>
<li>Did you get it?</li>
<li>Did you understand?</li>
<li>OK?</li>
</ul>


<p>And we are used to answer: &ldquo;Yes&rdquo;, &ldquo;Uhum&rdquo;.
But that is born of the Illusion of Competence.
To avoid it, now when I receive the question: &ldquo;Do you understand?&rdquo; My answer is: &ldquo;Can I explain to validate that I understood it?&rdquo;
By explaining what I just heard is a great opportunity to find gaps or raise points that were not covered by previous explanation.</p>

<h3>Doing exercises</h3>

<p>When I learn a new process|workflow I like to draw it and show it to how explained it to me. That&rsquo;s a good way to be sure that I&rsquo;m able to reproduce the process|workflow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2015: year's resolutions]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/2015-years-resolutions/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T13:49:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/2015-years-resolutions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are my new year&rsquo;s resolutions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Run a 5k race</li>
<li>Read 12 tech books (1 by month in avg)</li>
<li>Move close to work (20~40 minutes of daily commute)</li>
<li>Get back to play/sing</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euler's Journey Problem 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/eulers-journey-problem-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-29T19:38:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rogeralmeida.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/eulers-journey-problem-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I decided to start a project where I gonna implement the same problem in many languages. I always wanted to compare how different programming languages face some coding challenges. I don&rsquo;t want to prove that any language is better than other, althought I know that this kind of flame will happen.
To have a organized list of problems I gonna use the <a href="http://projecteuler.net/">Project Euler</a> problems.</p>

<!--more-->


<h1>First Problem: Multiples of 3 and 5</h1>

<p>So the first step of this jorney is the <a href="https://projecteuler.net/problem=1">Multiples of 3 and 5</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>If we list all the natural numbers below 10 that are multiples of 3 or 5, we get 3, 5, 6 and 9. The sum of these multiples is 23.
Find the sum of all the multiples of 3 or 5 below 1000.</p></blockquote>

<p>And here are the may implementations:</p>

<h2>Java 1.8</h2>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>SumMutiplesOf3And5</span><a href='https://github.com/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/blob/master/problems/1/java1.8/src/main/java/com/github/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/SumMultiplesOf3And5.java'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='Java'><span class='line'><span class="kn">package</span> <span class="n">com</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">github</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">rogeralmeida</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">eulersjourney</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="cm">/**</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="cm">* Created by ralmeid on 12/25/14.</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="cm">*/</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">SumMultiplesOf3And5</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">static</span> <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">main</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">String</span><span class="o">...</span> <span class="n">args</span><span class="o">){</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">Integer</span> <span class="n">sum</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">for</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="kt">int</span> <span class="n">number</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">;</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="o">;</span> <span class="n">number</span><span class="o">++){</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="k">if</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">3</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">5</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">){</span>
</span><span class='line'>              <span class="n">sum</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="n">number</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">System</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">out</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">printf</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="s">&quot;The sum of multiples of 3 and 5 below 1000 is %d&quot;</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="n">sum</span><span class="o">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Not much to say about the Java version. It is a little verbose, but still very easy to teach to programming students, as there&rsquo;s no hidden concept here. Everything is very explicit.</p>

<h2>Scala</h2>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Multiples</span><a href='https://github.com/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/blob/master/problems/1/scala/src/Multiples.scala'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='Scala'><span class='line'><span class="k">object</span> <span class="nc">Multiples</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="n">main</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="n">args</span><span class="k">:</span> <span class="kt">Array</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="kt">String</span><span class="o">])</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">var</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="k">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">var</span> <span class="n">sum</span> <span class="k">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">for</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">number</span> <span class="k">&lt;-</span> <span class="mi">1</span> <span class="n">to</span> <span class="mi">999</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">3</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">5</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">){</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="n">sum</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="n">number</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">printf</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="s">&quot;The sum of multiples of 3 and 5 bellow 1000 is %d&quot;</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="n">sum</span><span class="o">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I do not code in Scala, but have decided to add it to my toolbet in 2015. So I will make an effort to implement every problem in Scala as well.
I hope there&rsquo;s a less verbose way to do it in Scala, because I&rsquo;m not happy with this code.
One point that I would like to highlight here is the way to create a <a href="http://www.scala-lang.org/api/current/index.html#scala.collection.immutable.Range">Range</a> <code>1 to 999</code>. Also you can filter the for&rsquo;s enumerables without executing the for body.</p>

<hr />

<p>Yes, I&rsquo;ve found a better way of doing it in Scala. Check this out:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Multiples</span><a href='https://github.com/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/blob/master/problems/1/scala/src/Multiples.scala'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='Scala'><span class='line'><span class="k">object</span> <span class="nc">Multiples</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="n">main</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="n">args</span><span class="k">:</span> <span class="kt">Array</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="kt">String</span><span class="o">])</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">val</span> <span class="n">total</span> <span class="k">=</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="mi">1</span> <span class="n">to</span> <span class="mi">999</span><span class="o">).</span><span class="n">toList</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">filter</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">number</span> <span class="k">=&gt;</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">3</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">5</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">).</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">reduce</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="kt">Int</span><span class="o">]((</span><span class="n">accumulator</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="n">number</span><span class="o">)</span> <span class="k">=&gt;</span> <span class="n">accumulator</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">number</span><span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">printf</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="s">&quot;The sum of multiples of 3 and 5 bellow 1000 is %d&quot;</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="n">total</span><span class="o">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>First create a Range from 1 to 999.
Then coarse it to a List.
Then filter the list to get just the multiples of 3 or 5.
Then reduce the list using a accumulator.
I do liked this version, very concise, but the syntax is not that clear yet.</p>

<h2>Javascript</h2>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>multiples.js</span><a href='https://github.com/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/blob/master/problems/1/javascript/multiples.js'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='Javascript'><span class='line'><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">sum</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">number</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="nx">number</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="nx">number</span><span class="o">++</span><span class="p">){</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">3</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="nx">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">5</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">){</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">sum</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="nx">number</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;The sum of multiples of 3 and 5 bellow 1000 is &quot;</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="nx">sum</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Not much to say here, very straightforward.</p>

<h2>Python 2</h2>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>multiples.py</span><a href='https://github.com/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/blob/master/problems/1/python2/multiples.py'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='Python'><span class='line'><span class="n">multiples</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">sum</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="n">number</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="nb">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">3</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="ow">or</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">5</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)])</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">print</span> <span class="s">&quot;The sum of multiples of 3 and 5 bellow 1000 is {}&quot;</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">format</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">multiples</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The more I touch Python, more I like it.
It uses the <a href="https://docs.python.org/2/library/functions.html">range</a> function to generate the list of number from 1 to 999.
It uses <a href="https://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/datastructures.html">List Comprehension</a> to generate a list with only the multiples <code>[number for number in range(1, 1000) if (number % 3 == 0) or (number % 5 == 0)]</code> then it uses the <code>sum()</code> function to sum up the multiples.</p>

<h2>Ruby</h2>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>mutiples.rb</span><a href='https://github.com/rogeralmeida/eulersjourney/blob/master/problems/1/ruby/multiples.rb'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='Ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">sum</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">.</span><span class="mi">999</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">select</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="o">|</span><span class="n">number</span><span class="o">|</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">3</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="ow">or</span> <span class="n">number</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="mi">5</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">reduce</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="ss">:+</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;The sum of multiples of 3 and 5 is </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">sum</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">&quot;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>My favorite version so far.
First I like the way to create the range <code>(1..999)</code>. Like the Scala way it stills a little bit magical but this is it, or you have a Global function like Python or you have some sintax to recognize that you are creating a range.
The <code>select</code> method is very useful to filter a collection. The <code>reduce</code> method receives a symbol with the method that should be called to reduce the list, and it understand that it has to accumulate the value.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
